<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Black Garlic UK Ltd]]></title><description><![CDATA[Our Original Black Garlic is carefully chosen, high quality, raw garlic that has been expertly aged using nothing but heat and humidity.]]></description><link>https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/blog-1</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 03:51:37 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/blog-feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Beyond the Basics: How to Use Black Garlic in Innovative Ways]]></title><description><![CDATA[Find out more about how to use Black Garlic in innovative ways.]]></description><link>https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/post/how-to-use-black-garlic-in-innovative-ways</link><guid isPermaLink="false">66b6203abc3afa5f6d8fcb3e</guid><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 14:40:11 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_e716ec56aed7425d80be7c1955867ba8~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_740,h_194,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Original Black Garlic</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Black Garlic is far more versatile than you might think. The deep, mellow sweetness and rich umami flavor have been captivating chefs for years, but it&apos;s easy for home cooks to give lots of dishes a unique twist.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>Black Garlic Aioli</strong></p>
<p>Blend Black Garlic cloves with egg yolks, lemon juice, and olive oil for a smooth, flavorful aioli that pairs perfectly with everything from fries to grilled seafood. </p>
<p><strong>Try This:</strong> Use Black Garlic aioli on burgers, or as a dip for roasted vegetables.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>Black Garlic and Miso Glaze</strong></p>
<p>Take your favourite protein to new heights, combine our Original Black Garlic paste with miso, soy sauce, and a touch of honey. This glaze is perfect for brushing over salmon, chicken, or tofu before roasting or grilling. The umami-rich combination of Black Garlic and miso creates a savory-sweet crust that’s simply irresistible.</p>
<p><strong>Try This:</strong> Use this glaze on eggplant or mushrooms for a satisfying vegetarian option.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>Black Garlic Butter</strong></p>
<p>Mix softened butter with finely chopped Black Garlic, fresh herbs like parsley or thyme, and a pinch of sea salt. This compound butter can be used to finish steaks, melt over grilled corn, or spread on crusty <u>bread.</u></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>Black Garlic and Fig Chutney</strong></p>
<p>Black Garlic’s sweet and tangy profile pairs beautifully with fruits like figs. Simmer Black Garlic with fresh figs, balsamic vinegar, and a touch of brown sugar to create a luscious chutney. This chutney is a fantastic accompaniment to cheese boards, roast meats, or even as a topping for your morning toast.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>Black Garlic Ice Cream</strong></p>
<p>If you’re feeling adventurous, try making Black Garlic ice cream. The result is a creamy, sweet, and slightly savoury dessert. Serve Black Garlic ice cream with a drizzle of honey or a sprinkle of sea salt for an extra layer of flavour.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>Black Garlic Pesto</strong></p>
<p>Blend Black Garlic with fresh basil, pine nuts, Parmesan cheese, and olive oil for a pesto that’s rich in umami and slightly sweet. This pesto is perfect for pasta, as a spread on sandwiches, or as a dip for veggies.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>Black Garlic Vinaigrette</strong></p>
<p>Whisk together Black Garlic paste, olive oil, balsamic vinegar, Dijon mustard, and a touch of honey. This vinaigrette is a perfect balance of sweet, tangy, and savoury, making it an excellent dressing for everything from simple greens to hearty grain salads.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<h3>Ready to Try </h3>
<p>If you want to experiment with these ideas or discover a new favourite dish, we have more recipes <u><a href="www.blackgarlic.co.uk/recipes" rel="noreferrer" target="_blank">here.</a></u></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);">Discover more about our range here </span><span style="color: var(--ricos-custom-link-color,var(--ricos-action-color,#116dff));"><span style="background-color: var(--ricos-custom-p-background-color,unset);"><a href="https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/range" target="_blank">Range | Black Garlic</a></span></span><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"> or go to </span><u><span style="color: var(--ricos-custom-link-color,var(--ricos-action-color,#116dff));"><span style="background-color: var(--ricos-custom-p-background-color,unset);"><a href="http://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/shop" rel="noreferrer" target="_blank">our shop</a></span></span></u><span style="color: rgb(0, 0, 0);"> to try for yourself!</span></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_e716ec56aed7425d80be7c1955867ba8~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_740,h_194,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why Snacking Can Be Good for You!]]></title><description><![CDATA[There comes a point in the afternoon when your energy starts to lag, making it difficult to stay focused and productive. Instead of...]]></description><link>https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/post/snacking</link><guid isPermaLink="false">66261fdc2e3776389dde5d08</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 08:51:26 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_a271d8d81e02465fae7f63c4f0d9494f~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_900,h_900,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Original Black Garlic</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There comes a point in the afternoon when your energy starts to lag, making it difficult to stay focused and productive. Instead of powering through and risking burnout, consider taking a snack break to recharge. Snacking doesn&apos;t have to be a negative habit; in fact, it can be a beneficial part of your day when you choose the right options.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>Brain-Healthy Snacks</strong></p>
<p>If you find yourself having trouble concentrating, reach for snacks that are good for your brain. Opt for nutrient-rich foods like fruits, vegetables, roasted chickpeas seasoned with spices, or air-popped popcorn. These snacks not only satisfy your hunger but also provide essential nutrients to keep your brain sharp and focused.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>Healthy Sweet Treats</strong></p>
<p>For those craving something sweet, there are healthy alternatives to ultra-processed snacks high in added sugar. One excellent option is our Original Black Garlic cloves. These sweet yet savoury delights offer a complex and mellow flavour profile, with umami notes reminiscent of molasses, tamarind, caramel, and dates.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Black garlic is a unique and healthy snack choice because it has No additives, no preservatives just 100% Black Garlic magic with twice the antioxidants of white garlic!</p>
<p> </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_11ce6d1e7166449eb0874cad2b901ed3~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_579,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p>By incorporating healthy snacks into your day, you can boost your energy levels and maintain your focus. Whether you prefer brain-healthy options or antioxidant-rich treats like black garlic, there&apos;s a variety of nutritious choices available to suit your taste and lifestyle. So, the next time you feel the afternoon slump, embrace the opportunity to enjoy a healthy snack break!</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Curious to try?</strong></p>
<p>Read more about our range here <a href="https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/range" target="_blank">Range | Black Garlic</a> or go to <u><a href="www.blackgarlic.co.uk/shop" rel="noreferrer" target="_blank">our shop</a></u> to try for yourself!</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>For recipes and inspiration of how to cook with Black Garlic <u><a href="www.blackgarlic.co.uk/recipes" rel="noreferrer" target="_blank">look here</a></u>. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_9199d35aae604201a4249d6c31b9b6b4~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_586,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[A Flavourful Collaboration: The Original Black Garlic x Chef Órfhlaith Noone]]></title><description><![CDATA[We're excited to announce we’re bringing together the exceptional taste of Black Garlic with Órfhlaith’s culinary expertise to elevate...]]></description><link>https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/post/orfhlaithnoone</link><guid isPermaLink="false">651d3a73da714b52f93e62de</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 10:19:38 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_ace8560e2c2641308fd98eec2d8e9029~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_640,h_304,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Katy </dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<p>We&apos;re excited to announce we’re bringing together the exceptional taste of Black Garlic with Órfhlaith’s culinary expertise to elevate your autumnal and winter dishes to a whole new level.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Meet Chef Órfhlaith Noone</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>Órfhlaith is committed to using high-quality ingredients and promoting a sustainable, plant-based lifestyle which aligns perfectly with the values of The Original Black Garlic.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>After training at the Ballymaloe Cookery School in Ireland Órfhlaith worked as a baker and chef in different guises, and has developed recipes for brands and platforms including Deliciously Ella and The Doctor’s Kitchen.  A qualified nutrition coach, she specialises in nourishing comfort food. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_8f1eb7ed52274de3802164ce2e0ef16b~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_640,h_853,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_e310671c5777487a9f46f1cabc3f2b9f~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_1bd35e65fc1f4a53a7e0e984c09c2b80~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_640,h_741,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Órfhlaith’s enthusiasm for our Black Garlic products is infectious. She appreciates the unique and intense flavours that Black Garlic brings to a dish. This collaboration is a testament to her belief in the exceptional taste and culinary potential of Black Garlic, particularly during the autumnal and winter seasons, as the rich, complex flavours of Black Garlic perfectly complement the hearty, comforting dishes that are a staple during the colder months. From soups and stews to roasts and sauces, the possibilities are endless.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Culinary Creations Await!</strong></p>
<p>We invite you to join us on this gastronomic journey filled with recipes that highlight the distinctive flavours of Black Garlic. Together.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Stay tuned for upcoming recipe releases and behind-the-scenes insights into Chef Órfhlaith Noone&apos;s culinary process.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Can&apos;t wait?  You can get lots of fantastic recipes <u><a href="https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/recipes-tips" target="_blank">right here</a></u>.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[What's the Buzz About Black Garlic?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Black Garlic is currently experiencing a surge in popularity, captivating both consumers and chefs alike. This unique ingredient has been...]]></description><link>https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/post/what-s-the-buzz-about-black-garlic</link><guid isPermaLink="false">64ccd44d3854fbcaa508337b</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 11:20:54 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_14916f16a6884973996a19ebf9e8c7b9~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_578,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Katy </dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Black Garlic is currently experiencing a surge in popularity, captivating both consumers and chefs alike. This unique ingredient has been widely embraced by the world of good, including manufacturers, leading to its inclusion in a diverse range of food products, from jams to indulgent chocolates.</h3>
<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_14916f16a6884973996a19ebf9e8c7b9~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_578,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<h3>The Budweiser Brewing Group has even released a special-edition pack of Smoked Salt and Black Garlic potato chips to support the Hospitality Action charity. And Halloween 2022 saw Heinz have a big hit with their vegan Black Garlic mayonnaise. Following the popularity of Aldi’s Christmas Black Garlic cheese, we’ve a strong feeling many other cheese makers have a BG version in the wings…</h3>
<p><br /></p>
<h3>Our Black Garlic is carefully chosen, premium quality, white garlic that’s been expertly aged with nothing but heat, humidity and love. The result is delicious Black Garlic, providing fantastic taste in cooking or superfood goodness in a healthy snack.  Its umami-richness makes it an ideal addition to anything you can think of – pizza, pasta, chillies, stir fries, sauces, dressings, marinades, soups, and even desserts.  </h3>
<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_9199d35aae604201a4249d6c31b9b6b4~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_586,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<h3>If you want to learn more about Black Garlic or want to talk pricing, stocking or anything commercial don&apos;t hesitate to get in touch with our team. You can reach us at hello@blackgarlic.co.uk.</h3>
<h3></h3>
<h3>For stockists <u><a href="https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/stockists" target="_blank">click here</a></u> or buy online <u><a href="https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/shop" target="_blank">here</a></u>.</h3>
<h3></h3>
<h3>Check out our <u><a href="https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/recipes-tips" target="_blank">recipe page</a></u> and social pages for ideas of how to use.</h3>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Introducing New Case Sizes and Clipstrips from The Original Black Garlic]]></title><description><![CDATA[We’ve some exciting new offerings for our customers and customers to be  To address the issue of space, we’re introducing new case...]]></description><link>https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/post/introducing-new-case-sizes-and-clipstrips-from-the-original-black-garlic</link><guid isPermaLink="false">64b00e7bb8332ffb7b321ebf</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 14:55:22 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_c7e3a1de80a94293a18bd5518b672cd0~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_826,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>nicola5712</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<p>We’ve some exciting new offerings for our customers and customers to be  To address the issue of space, we’re introducing new case sizes for our 50g peeled clove product (10 units) and 1 bulb boxes (8 units). </p>
<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_c7e3a1de80a94293a18bd5518b672cd0~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_826,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p>We’re also introducing a new format for retail customers - Clipstrips! These stylish strips are filled with ideas to use Black Garlic, the world&apos;s most delicious, luxurious, flavoursome, umami deep, diverse ingredient there is! We’re hoping these eye-catching displays will attract your customers&apos; attention to the wonders of OBG .</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>All of these new products are available now.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>If your NPD team are looking for a compelling and versatile flavour, guaranteed to shine in so many settings, don&apos;t hesitate to get in touch for a sample of our peeled cloves, bulbs or paste email hello@blackgarlic.co.uk</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Click to find out more about <u><a href="https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/wholesale" target="_blank">wholesale</a></u>.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>The Original Black Garlic - made with love  </p>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Channel 4 unwraps Black Garlic health and anti-ageing benefits]]></title><description><![CDATA[Find out more about Black Garlic in Channel 4’s Food Unwrapped programme, unveiling new research about Black Garlic’s health and anti-ageing]]></description><link>https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/post/channel-4-unwraps-black-garlic-health-and-anti-ageing-benefits</link><guid isPermaLink="false">63bc2c61a16b6af1e959b867</guid><category><![CDATA[food]]></category><category><![CDATA[health]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 15:53:44 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_4f563ce46420418f87195468a80fe1be~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_488,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Original Black Garlic</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Channel 4’s Food Unwrapped programme unveiled new research about Black Garlic’s health and anti-ageing benefits last week as part of its </strong><u><a href=" www.channel4.com/programmes/food-unwrapped " target="_blank"><strong>New Year Health Kick special</strong></a></u> </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_4f563ce46420418f87195468a80fe1be~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_488,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p>With ‘eating healthier’ accounting for 43% of New Year’s resolutions last year, Black Garlic is a top tip for boosting youth, whilst packing a punch of umami flavour, for anyone looking for healthy eating hacks in 2023.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The show unveiled research carried out by scientists at Manchester Metropolitan University (MMU), which suggests that Black Garlic may help to prevent the decline of kidney and blood vessel function, along with neuro-degenerative conditions, such as Alzheimer’s. Preliminary results of the research showed that Black Garlic may also help slow the signs of ageing too! </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Presenter, John Whaite, learned how early studies have shown that Black Garlic inhibits glycation, the spontaneous reaction of sugars and proteins in the food we eat, which is implicated in a variety of diseases and in ageing. The show highlighted how Black Garlic has shown even more promising results than conventional white garlic in lab tests, with research still ongoing.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">During the Food Unwrapped show, presenter, Kate Quilton, visited our production facility and tried The Original Black Garlic for the first time and loved the sweet balsamic flavour. She also learned how we take premium white garlic and transform it with a unique combination of heat, humidity and time. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_9e9d7ac011bf470aa1a39a9a662cc36d~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_b0630086d5b546b69616f32c24dd5732~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_942295f0c0264cd9903a70fdf46f75b9~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p>Our founder and CEO, Katy Heath, commented: “Black Garlic is not only an umami flavour bomb in the kitchen, but is also widely recognised for a multitude of health benefits, which are rapidly helping it to gain a wide fan base as a superfood. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Black Garlic’s health benefits are directly linked to its antioxidant profile – at least twice that of white garlic – which reduces harmful free radicals and helps protect cells from disease. Antioxidants can help reduce inflammation within the body, which is associated with chronic disease, and research shows that Black Garlic’s high antioxidant levels may help maintain good heart and brain function, lower cholesterol, improve circulation, and protect the immune system. It all adds up to an ingredient that transforms the flavour of all kinds of dishes, as well as doubling as a tasty real-food supplement.”</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Katy adds: “People want to be able to make exciting and flavoursome meals at home, discover new ingredients, and make choices that boost their health. The latest research indicates that Black Garlic may offer all of this, and help to reduce the signs of ageing too – no wonder it is such an on trend ingredient for restaurants, food manufacturers and home cooks alike!”</p>
<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_06648767c7054b0cb1897aaf234f62ee~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_c9efbb3b94a5459684f2101d92067988~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_b16c64f61e1e4edc93b0fc1a82d0d9f5~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p><u><a href="https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/stockists" target="_blank"><strong>For stockist click here</strong></a></u> and If you want exciting ways to try our Black Garlic cloves and paste, try one of our <u><a href="https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/recipes-tips" target="_blank">recipes.</a></u> </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Images from Channel 4 and Ricochet Ltd.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Original Black Garlic wins Great Taste 2022 award]]></title><description><![CDATA[We are excited to announce that our Original Black Garlic bulb and peeled cloves have been awarded the Great Taste award. Produced in the...]]></description><link>https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/post/the-original-black-garlic-wins-great-taste-2022-award</link><guid isPermaLink="false">62ece940333c3c6721889ebf</guid><category><![CDATA[Corporate]]></category><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 10:00:50 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_12e78d3bb5914280940a4410a50cde96~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Original Black Garlic</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_12e78d3bb5914280940a4410a50cde96~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_6dc5ad84065f4bc597a09830faec9bd8~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_426,h_414,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_17ed4c6069194b58b09b71ec074b099f~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_709,h_710,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><strong>We are excited to announce that our Original Black Garlic bulb and peeled cloves have been awarded the Great Taste award.</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Produced in the UK with only heat and time, Black Garlic is carefully chosen, high quality, raw garlic that has been expertly aged. The result is delicious Black cloves that add umami depth and richness to almost any cuisine when used as a cooking paste, soft jelly like cloves bursting with flavour when used as whole pieces as an ingredient and a healthy sweet snack with a unique savoury edge if snacked on straight from the bulb or pot.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Katy Heath from The Original Black Garlic commented: “We are delighted to have won a Great Taste award for our bulb and peeled cloves, and we’re very proud to be adding the iconic black and gold Great Taste logo to our range”</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>The Judging Process</strong></p>
<p>More than 14,000 products were put through the competition’s rigorous blind judging process; and The Original Black Garlic was dubbed a “Commendable” product at the world’s most coveted food and drink awards. </p>
<p>Described as having a complexity of flavours sweet, umami, cocoa, caramel, with a long and developing finish, and a smoky fragrance that is subtle and enticing. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>What is Great Taste?</strong></p>
<p>Recognised as a stamp of excellence and actively sought out by food lovers and retailers alike, Great Taste, organised by the Guild of Fine Food, values taste above all else. All products in the line-up for judging are blind-tasted: every product is removed from its packaging so it cannot be identified, before entering a robust, layered judging process.</p>
<p>This year, the judging took place over 90 days across two judging locations (Dorset and London) with a panel of more than 500 judges. This year’s line-up saw food and drink products submitted from a staggering 110 different countries from across the world. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>For stockist see our </strong><u><a href="www.blackgarlic.co.uk" target="_blank"><strong>website</strong></a></u><strong> </strong></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fine dining at its very best!]]></title><description><![CDATA[The OBG team had an amazing day at the recent London Social Kitchen event, sharing a unique behind the scenes look at the world of...]]></description><link>https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/post/fine-dining-at-its-very-best</link><guid isPermaLink="false">615d7956b5194100160b0551</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 10:35:03 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_bfc825bc41e34e3db2c3187a4145dc1d~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Original Black Garlic</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">The OBG team had an amazing day at the recent London Social Kitchen event, sharing a unique behind the scenes look at the world of talented Chefs; Daniel Britton, James Peck, Jay Copeland, Ben Davis, Kenny Markham, Steve Thompson and Pascal Dalpra.</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_b6e146ea7b2241569367379fb5cbafc3~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_e73f5bbf308a49c382830c2b436f8254~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_bfc825bc41e34e3db2c3187a4145dc1d~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_16ab53e4107d4aa9bd9a14c980c3c5f9~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p>
<span style="background-color: #ffffff;">The dishes they created exceeded their &apos;fine dining at its very best&apos; tag and all our expectations of how to use our Original Black Garlic at the highest level.</span></p>
<p>Black Garlic tart, potato terrine, honey truffle, and bean blossom by James Peck.
</p>
<p>Agaricus kimchi hash brown, rosehip, fermented tomato with Original Black Garlic by Steve Thompson.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Roasted and smoked autumn vegetables, celeriac purée, Hogweed granola and Original Black Garlic ketchup by Daniel Britten.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Pork and gin Rillettes, with crispy chard, puffed quinoa and Original Black Garlic ketchup by Daniel Britten.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>All created with <span style="background-color: #ffffff;">produce from Fairfax London, Koppertcress, </span>Ibéricos COVAP<span style="background-color: #ffffff;">, Vichy Catalan and of course our Original Black Garlic.</span>

<span style="background-color: #ffffff;">Beautifully presented on the tableware of Rak and set in the fabulous surroundings of the Lockhart Innovation Centre.</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_513d5c04ca5d41e08275b669d06a74ed~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_48bf6957ef4849aaa70489079cf61740~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_9d451a012ab54fa5a28f609bd19db420~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_9575ad01b06e4bd39f6d1497fda8b1e4~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p>
 Photography by Majella from Pavlova and Cream.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/pavlovaandcream/" target="_blank"><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">@pavlovaandcream</span></a><span style="background-color: #ffffff;"> @londonkitchensocial </span><a href="https://www.instagram.com/danielpbritten/" target="_blank"><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">@danielpbritten</span></a><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">, </span><a href="https://www.instagram.com/jamespecckk/" target="_blank"><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">@jamespecckk</span></a><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">, </span><a href="https://www.instagram.com/chefjaaay/" target="_blank"><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">@chefjaaay</span></a><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">, </span><a href="https://www.instagram.com/bendavischef/" target="_blank"><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">@bendavischef</span></a><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">, </span><a href="https://www.instagram.com/chefkennyskitchen/" target="_blank"><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">@chefkennyskitchen</span></a><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">, </span><a href="https://www.instagram.com/chefstevethompson/" target="_blank"><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">@chefstevethompson</span></a><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">  </span><a href="https://www.instagram.com/morgansbargrilluk/" target="_blank"><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">@morgansbargrilluk</span></a><span style="background-color: #ffffff;"> </span><a href="https://www.instagram.com/fairfaxlondon/" target="_blank"><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">@fairfaxlondon</span></a><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">, </span><a href="https://www.instagram.com/koppertcressuk/" target="_blank"><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">@koppertcressuk</span></a><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">, </span><a href="https://www.instagram.com/ibericoscovap/" target="_blank"><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">@ibericoscovap</span></a><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">, </span><a href="https://www.instagram.com/vichycatalan/" target="_blank"><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">@vichycatalan</span></a><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">  </span><a href="https://www.instagram.com/rakporcelaineurope/" target="_blank"><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">@rakporcelaineurope</span></a><span style="background-color: #ffffff;"> </span><a href="https://www.instagram.com/bunzllockhart/" target="_blank"><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">@bunzllockhart</span></a><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">  </span><a href="https://www.instagram.com/pavlovaandcream/" target="_blank"><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">@pavlovaandcream</span></a><span style="background-color: #ffffff;"> </span></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Introducing our food partner - Hawkhead Whiskey Smoked]]></title><description><![CDATA[Our Original Black Garlic flavours the Hawkhead Whiskey Smoked Black Garlic Salt, made using triple filtered, small batch Atlantic salt...]]></description><link>https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/post/introducing-our-food-partner-hawkhead-whiskey-smoked</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60d2f4b50032b000154fbc93</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 14:00:50 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_c1dff73bb0a14a239f9e96a3c9644eb5~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_540,h_564,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Original Black Garlic</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Our Original Black Garlic flavours the Hawkhead Whiskey Smoked Black Garlic Salt, made using triple filtered, small batch Atlantic salt from the UK. Free from preservatives, the light crystal flakes are perfect for absorbing all the warmth and sweetness of the smoky aromas.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>They take our Black Garlic with it&apos;s has a uniquely mellow, umami flavour, smoke it and crumble it into their salt for a robust and deep flavour profile.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>It&apos;s already won a 3 Star great taste award from last year and have recently won for best flavoured salt in the Scottish retail food and drinks award.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_c1dff73bb0a14a239f9e96a3c9644eb5~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_540,h_564,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_32c651b358df489ebab3abda1338a1da~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_720,h_720,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_f2c6e3bc1fe14addbcb222d511ab78ba~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_720,h_720,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_bd7ea39942fc4a8bac6a765dfd2642e0~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_150,h_267,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The secrets out, Yotam Ottolenghi’s has confirmed Black Garlic as his go-to ingredient.]]></title><description><![CDATA[In the Guardian online article last Sunday, the well known chef and author confirmed Black Garlic is his secret ingredient, using it to...]]></description><link>https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/post/the-secrets-out-yotam-ottolenghi-s-has-confirmed-black-garlic-as-his-go-to-ingredient</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60d2eadeb50b87001537a700</guid><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 07:51:17 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_ea56e40933e247dcb99fdbffc5dbf4c8~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_640,h_640,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Original Black Garlic</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<p>In the <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/20/yotam-ottolenghis-secret-ingredient-black-garlic" target="_blank">Guardian online</a> article last Sunday, the well known chef and author confirmed Black Garlic is his secret ingredient, using it to add flavour and depth to roast chicken, gravy and vegan Bolognese.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>In the feature <a href="https://ottolenghi.co.uk/" target="_blank">Ottolenghi</a> said;</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>&quot;Black garlic has a really lovely deep umami flavour that reminds me of liquorice and balsamic vinegar. It’s quite sweet and savoury at the same time, with some hint of garlic in the background.</p>
<p>Essentially, it’s just fresh garlic heads left at a particularly low temperature – between 60-90C with a specific humidity for, I think, a couple of weeks. The heads dry out and cook, and turn from the wonderful creamy colour that we know to totally black and shriveled.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>I use it a lot with fat. I do a black-garlic butter: crush the black garlic with the side of a knife or a pestle and mortar, then whip or mix it with soft butter. If I roast a chicken – even a turkey – I often put this black-garlic butter underneath the skin. It gives the chicken a nice flavour, and the cooking liquids – the base for a gravy – have a particular black garlic depth.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>I use it for vegetarian and vegan cooking as well. I would use it in a vegan bolognese based on lentils and barley, and it’s really good for a risotto. I also like to mix it with other garlic. In the last book, <em>Flavour</em>, we’ve got a recipe for three garlic butter. By three garlic, I mean black garlic, confit garlic and raw garlic. Together it gives you all these iterations of garlic. To make a quick yoghurt sauce, you crush your black garlic cloves and add it to yoghurt with fresh garlic. It makes the most beautiful barbecue style sauce that’s great on roasted vegetables.&quot;</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>At the Original Black Garlic we’re huge fans of the extremely talented Chef, his restaurants and recipe books and can&apos;t wait to see more amazing dishes created with our range.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Join the Black Garlic Revolution! (you&apos;ll be in good company!)</p>
<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_c2521a453f8347239bd50d86dc985798~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_984,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_bd53e1ec81d349e4bbde5328f8cc6f65~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Original Black Garlic Goes Organic!]]></title><description><![CDATA[Launch of our Organic version of our Original Black Garlic cloves pot is on shelves now at Planet Organic. ]]></description><link>https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/post/the-original-black-garlic-goes-organic</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60bf499ed11e2500156288fb</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 11:47:45 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_4d59fe62720d4085bee9ccb3f7c0f40f~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Original Black Garlic</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A limited edition, Organic version of our Original Black Garlic cloves pot is on shelves now at <u><a href="https://www.planetorganic.com/products/the-original-black-garlic-peeled-cloves-50g" target="_blank">Planet Organic.</a></u> </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Demand for organic foods is growing and rightly so, at OBG we want everyone to have access to healthy, sustainably produced food.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>This was the driver to work with <u><a href="https://www.planetorganic.com/products/the-original-black-garlic-peeled-cloves-50g" target="_blank">Planet Organic</a></u> to create this new addition to our Black Garlic range. It&apos;s made with only one ingredient, the best 100% organic raw garlic, and absolutely no additives or preservatives!</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>We then expertly age the organic garlic, using nothing but heat and humidity. The result is sticky and delicious Black Garlic, providing fantastic taste in cooking or a healthy, tasty snack.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>The convenient peeled garlic tubs mean you can easily add them to any dish to enhance the flavour or eat direct from the pot!</p>
<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_4d59fe62720d4085bee9ccb3f7c0f40f~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_872ea9e05de4490595de766f8cf8e5d7~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_2d82fc4067e44a128b58de86e6b20436~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p>We have held Soil Association certification and SALSA approval for some time, as we believe it is the most transparent way to show that we are producing our product to the highest standards, we also recently received Vegan certification for the entire Original Black Garlic range.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a57774_b8553bd8d978483e871e0a6f78138492~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_274,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Original Black Garlic range is certified vegan!]]></title><description><![CDATA[We're proud to announce the fantastic news that our entire range is now certified vegan by the Vegan Society, meaning it's free from...]]></description><link>https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/post/the-original-black-garlic-range-is-certified-vegan</link><guid isPermaLink="false">606eb9b15cc3ff00b29466db</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 08:38:45 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_84b29f8af11842759b47e5db9bbac6db~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Original Black Garlic</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="color: #000000;">We&apos;re proud to announce the fantastic news that our entire range is now certified vegan by the Vegan Society, meaning it&apos;s free from animal ingredients and not tested on animals.</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">Going vegan is a great opportunity to learn more about nutrition and cooking, and improve your diet. Getting your nutrients from plant foods allows more room in your diet for health-promoting options like whole grains, fruit, nuts, seeds and vegetables, which are packed full of beneficial fibre, vitamins and minerals.</span></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_b95ebc83f9dc46bdbf6ecbb4f2364e3c~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_573,h_552,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_a372867d0e594505bc8bcc365bf8951d~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_603,h_455,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_6dc5ad84065f4bc597a09830faec9bd8~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_426,h_414,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_84b29f8af11842759b47e5db9bbac6db~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Black garlic gives so many exciting ways to enhance your home meat free cuisine, as well as the added benefit of your physical resistance to disease.  Think of it as your third seasoning; salt-pepper-black garlic and add it to dishes for the richness that it is sometimes hard to achieve without the fatty and saltiness of meat.  As well as carrying its own umami taste it deepens the flavour of your other ingredients adding depth and piquancy to vegan meals.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">The Vegan Society, the world’s first, is an educational membership charity that promotes and supports people to adopt a vegan lifestyle. The Vegan Society was formed in 1944, by a group of vegetarians who recognised the ethical compromises of eating eggs and dairy products.</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">The Trademark helps people identify a product that is free-from animal ingredients and has not been tested on animals.</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">If you have any questions about our certified products or the Vegan Trademark, feel free to contact us at any time, we are happy to help you out.</span></p>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Introducing our food partner - The Hawkshead Relish Company.]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Hawkshead Relish are a multi award winning artisan food producer from the Lake District Town of Hawkshead. The now have a range of...]]></description><link>https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/post/hawkshead-relish-blog</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60473e2ce869500016ddc010</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 09:56:14 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_e0d2949848ea43a3bfc8c6a3e4b08fa1~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Original Black Garlic</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Hawkshead Relish are a multi award winning artisan food producer from the Lake District Town of Hawkshead.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>The now have a range of over 100 relishes and preserves. All their products are still made by hand using traditional open pans and are free from nuts, gluten, additives and preservatives as well as all being suitable for vegetarians and most are vegan friendly.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_eb68f9c08b914b5881cc1cdb41acae72~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_525,h_185,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p>They only use quality ingredients to enhance the flavour of their products, so you can really taste the difference.  We’re proud that our Original Black Garlic is in their award winning Black Garlic Ketchup and Pickle.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_cc39dd46f8e842ce809d31e7730eb190~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_522,h_173,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p>Nigel Barden TV and Radio Chef is a huge fan, featuring it on the BBC Radio 2 Drivetime show he said &quot;A little goes a long way and rarely have I seen the Radio 2 Drivetime team silenced by a condiment!&quot;</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_ffb1362c23b3414e9b21270da638eeae~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_520,h_185,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p>We look forward to seeing what other products they create with our Original Black Garlic.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Click here to see their Black Garlic range <a href="https://bit.ly/OBGHawkshead?fbclid=IwAR2JD_VY0mTKZVMcx1lfCGYwEnSuw_UhiAfQ8KpCZM7d-lnlkEsPjlOKCY0" target="_blank">bit.ly/OBGHawkshead</a></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[International Women's Day - March 8, 2021]]></title><description><![CDATA[In recognition of International Women’s Day 2021, The Original Black Garlic (OBG) are celebrating our CEO and Founder, Katy Heath. Katy...]]></description><link>https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/post/womens-day-blog</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6045ec475a14e50015eaf795</guid><category><![CDATA[Corporate]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 09:45:20 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_a372867d0e594505bc8bcc365bf8951d~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_603,h_455,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Original Black Garlic</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">In recognition of International Women’s Day 2021, The Original Black Garlic (OBG) are celebrating our CEO and Founder, Katy Heath.</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">Katy has had a highly successful career sourcing and distributing fresh produce globally. She’s a keen traveller and first came across Black Garlic in Asia in the early 2000s. As a dedicated foodie and talented entrepreneur, Katy realised that this amazing superfood deserved to be propelled to the world’s attention, which started her mission and the establishment of The Original Black Garlic.</span></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_a372867d0e594505bc8bcc365bf8951d~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_603,h_455,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/92d1e6_097ba7385f424395afec32920ffca5f8~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_785,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/5a475d_2e29a85903534bc98b5cc1f971b83574~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_961,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">As well as leading the OBG business, Katy is Mum to 9-year-old Nate and passionate about animals (pets and other!) and living a life to remember. She has always believed in empowering women in business and developing talent through a supportive framework of coaching, mentoring, and giving people the freedom to be the best version of themselves. She drives a culture of inclusiveness and opportunity at OBG and the values of the brand mirror that of Katy – collaborative, thoughtful and with integrity at the heart of what we do and who we are.</span></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/5a475d_96ca8460f2c3480884c1a8db95fb0fbb~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_41e05cc913c74b66945e381fa936e1d2~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_577,h_536,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_75016e751af7454d97652f1fde93219b~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_827,h_819,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">Black Garlic has been tipped by Waitrose as one of the food trends of 2021and we believe this is largely due to the efforts of Katy and our much-respected Chef collaborators, who have brought this umami flavour bomb front and centre of the good food sector. </span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">Looking outside of the business, when reflecting on the past 12 months, Katy says:</span></p>
<p>“The pandemic has given us time to pause; people have found humanity again, when it looked like the human race was going backwards and de-humanising.  Personally, it has reinforced the idea that the best things in life are free and a realisation that we don’t need that much, but what we really need (as humans) is each other, hope and laughter.”</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Katy acknowledges the huge debt of gratitude we owe the individuals working in the NHS and if anyone should be celebrated on IWD, it should be the women across the globe, in all walks of life, who have given everything to get us through this incredible time.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>We salute you.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<h2>#ChooseToChallenge  #IWD2021</h2>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to create the perfect cheese board]]></title><description><![CDATA[Cheese boards and charcuterie platters are becoming more and more popular, quick and easy to prepare and a real crowd-pleaser.  Perfect...]]></description><link>https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/post/how-to-create-the-perfect-cheese-board</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5fe1ab7e1e5c7d0017384320</guid><pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 08:51:03 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_d87e12a3802c4cfdb7b76f11f84a789c~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Katy </dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="color: #484543;"><span style="background-color: #e9e8e7;">Cheese boards and </span></span>charcuterie<span style="color: #484543;"><span style="background-color: #e9e8e7;"> platters are becoming more and more popular, quick and easy to prepare and a real crowd-pleaser.  </span></span>Perfect for parties, entertaining or just a cosy night in, you can&apos;t fail to make a delicious centre piece. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>For us it&apos;s all about taking these amazing flavours and tastes that you love and enhancing them with our Original Black Garlic.  B<span style="color: #262626;"><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">lack garlic is an incredible flavour bomb and with cheese, it&apos;s a match made in food heaven! </span></span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #262626;"><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">If you haven’t tried them together, now is the perfect chance!</span></span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>You will need</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li><p><strong>An eye-catching board </strong> Go for square, rectangular, or round to suit your preference. Try slate or wood, but if your don&apos;t have those, you can use a plate or a cutting board. </p></li>
  <li><p><strong>Cheese</strong> Variety is important, try lots of different textures and flavours.</p></li>
  <li><p><strong>Meats </strong>Prosciutto, salami, chorizo, the choice is yours.</p></li>
  <li><p><strong>The magic</strong> Black garlic, our whole bulbs look as good as they taste and they will certainly get your cheeseboard noticed!  For convenience our peeled cloves can be eaten whole or sliced.</p></li>
  <li><p><strong>Breads</strong> Fresh bread, bread sticks, and a variety of crackers.</p></li>
  <li><p><strong>Garnishes </strong>This is the time to get really creative with pickles and dips, fruit and fresh herbs.</p></li>
</ul>
<p>
Now to ensemble your creation, look at different heights, and balancing the items out across the board.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Enjoy!</p>
<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_d87e12a3802c4cfdb7b76f11f84a789c~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Festive wishes from the Original Black Garlic team]]></title><description><![CDATA[It’s very hard to start writing about 2020 without feeling a little overwhelmed or consumed by cliché - this year has been so challenging...]]></description><link>https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/post/festive-wishes-from-the-original-black-garlic-team</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5fe07d2b2f23530017c42c5c</guid><category><![CDATA[food]]></category><category><![CDATA[xmas]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 11:26:39 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_bcdda6b2b7ca43e7bde101578b1651a8~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_780,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Katy </dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_bd2c34f00bf748708de8e380120d5e98~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_780,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p>It’s very hard to start writing about 2020 without feeling a little overwhelmed or consumed by cliché - this year has been so challenging across the world and for all societies. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>We would like to take this opportunity to thank our loyal followers for their support and to wish everyone reading this a very peaceful Christmas.  </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>In reflecting on the year, we wanted to acknowledge some of the highlights for the OBG team and business, that were all driven through great collaborations and partnerships, for which we are very proud. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>In the world of chefs our Original Black Garlic was acknowledged by Yotam Ottolenghi as a must-have flavour bomb in his legendary new book Flavour and OBG was also included in his sell out Christmas hamper.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_9cf7c920e8d947b19041ebe3467c3e58~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_c2521a453f8347239bd50d86dc985798~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_984,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_0c29b15f835147eba1411a766a192cb3~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_648,h_617,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p>OBG moved into new realms with its inclusion in a traditional favourite of Sticky Toffee Pudding by Dan Britten and we reached the Master Chef final with an amazing Chef, Louisa Ellis. Louisa also found time to generously make free meals for the NHS during lockdown which deserves huge respect and thanks from us.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_4cfd860d0b3b498b84866aebbb569120~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_620,h_413,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_6e7322f9dfda48c3a0069056c023f118~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_828,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_14c855dfc4ec4de8beb11f46f5d46c96~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_825,h_475,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p>We were very excited to launch our NEW 1Shot product – paste in an easy-to-use single serving – which has proven to be a fabulous addition to our range. To read more about our flavour bomb sachets <u><a href="https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/post/try-our-new-flavour-bomb" target="_blank">click here.</a></u></p>
<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_c4fa67314b854fd7947819fc89f5990e~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_37cabc5d29794111920151a22f0b4659~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_f5c732cd162a4b348a885e266861570f~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p>We’ve really enjoyed working with teams such as Olivado Oils to buddy up our products and capture the magic when OBG meets other great tastes and textures (OBG loves a party!). And we’d like to thank publications, including Olive magazine, for helping spread the word on the difference OBG can bring to every-day cooking.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_f328234c3c4843ebb11f5c4ce2cb94d5~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_494,h_577,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_75016e751af7454d97652f1fde93219b~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_827,h_819,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_bb9dd0976d4e4c929c45a04e4c7ecf1f~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_826,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p>The OBG team is very excited by the prospect of beginnings and discoveries in 2021 and look forward to sharing these with you all. What we’ve learned this year is that staying connected with people and working together is what really makes the world go round and we’re very grateful to everyone who has shared that ride with us. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Wishing you all a Happy Christmas...</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Win a Flavour Hamper by Ottolenghi]]></title><description><![CDATA[*** We are very excited to announce the winner of our fabulous Ottolenghi hamper giveaway is ... LAURA GREGG - CONGRATULATIONS !!...]]></description><link>https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/post/win-a-flavour-hamper-by-ottolenghi</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5fbf7d706cbbd80017ee7f98</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 09:13:50 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_1e319c0973e843c5b028372e247ca961~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_780,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Katy </dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_1e319c0973e843c5b028372e247ca961~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_780,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p>*** We are very excited to announce the winner of our fabulous Ottolenghi hamper giveaway is ...</p>
<p>LAURA GREGG - CONGRATULATIONS !!</p>
<p>Thank you to everyone who entered, we hope we helped to share some love this Christmas ***</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>Share the LOVE this Christmas</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Want to surprise a special person or say thank you to someone who’s helped you out in 2020?</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>We’re giving away a coveted<u><a href="https://ottolenghi.co.uk/shop/hampers-and-gifts/flavour-hamper" target="_blank"> Flavour Hamper by Ottolenghi</a></u> (worth £100!), which includes our Original Black Garlic - the flavour bomb that keeps on giving! and we’d like you to nominate someone to receive this fabulous gift. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Include as many people as you wish!</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>How to enter</strong></p>
<p>Head to our social media pages on <u><a href="https://www.facebook.com/OriginalBlackGarlic" target="_blank">Facebook</a></u> and <u><a href="https://www.instagram.com/originalblackgarlicuk/" target="_blank">Instagram</a></u>.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Just LIKE and SHARE our page and include your nomination(s) in the comment in any of our 12 Days of Christmas competition posts.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>The competition ends at midnight on the 12th Dec and the lucky winner will be contact and their name announced on our social media pages on the 14th Dec.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Sprinkle a little magic this Christmas….best of luck!</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Ts &amp; Cs</p>
<ol>
  <li><p>The promoter is Black Garlic (UK) Ltd.</p></li>
  <li><p>The competition is open to residents of the United Kingdom aged 18 years or over except employees of Black Garlic (UK) Ltd and their close relatives and anyone otherwise connected with the organisation or judging of the competition.</p></li>
  <li><p>There is no entry fee and no purchase necessary to enter this competition.</p></li>
  <li><p>By entering this competition, an entrant is indicating his/her agreement to be bound by these terms and conditions.</p></li>
  <li><p>Route to entry for the competition and details of how to enter are via Facebook, Twitter and Instagram</p></li>
  <li><p>Only one entry will be accepted per person. Multiple entries from  the same person will be disqualified.</p></li>
  <li><p>Closing date for entry will be 12/12/20. After this date the no further entries to the competition will be permitted.</p></li>
  <li><p>No responsibility can be accepted for entries not received for whatever reason.</p></li>
  <li><p>The promoter reserves the right to cancel or amend the competition and these terms and conditions without notice in the event of a catastrophe, war, civil or military disturbance, act of God or any actual or anticipated breach of any applicable law or regulation or any other      event outside of the promoter’s control. Any changes to the competition  will be notified to entrants as soon as possible by the promoter.</p></li>
  <li><p>The promoter is not responsible for inaccurate prize details supplied to any entrant by any third party connected with this competition.</p></li>
  <li><p>The prize is as follows  The Flavour Hamper by Ottolenghi </p></li>
  <li><p>The prize is as stated and no cash or other alternatives will be offered. The prizes are not transferable. Prizes are subject to availability and we reserve the right to substitute any prize with another of equivalent value without giving notice.</p></li>
  <li><p>Winners will be chosen on 14th Dec 20 at random by software, from all entries received.</p></li>
  <li><p>The winner will be notified by DM on Twitter, Facebook or Instagram.  If the winner cannot be contacted or do not claim the prize within 14 days of notification, we reserve the right to withdraw the prize from the winner and pick a replacement winner. The promoter will notify the winner when and where the prize can be collected / is delivered.</p></li>
  <li><p>The promoter’s decision in respect of all matters to do with the competition will be final and no correspondence will be entered into.</p></li>
  <li><p>By entering this competition, an entrant is indicating his/her agreement to be bound by these terms and conditions.</p></li>
  <li><p>The winner agrees to the use of his/her name and image in any publicity material, as well as their entry. Any personal data relating to the winner or any other entrants will be used solely in accordance with current [UK] data protection legislation and will not be disclosed to a third party without the entrant’s prior consent.</p></li>
  <li><p>This promotion is in no way sponsored, endorsed or administered by, or associated with, Facebook, Twitter or any other Social Network. </p></li>
</ol>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>#contest</strong></p>
<p><strong>#giveaway</strong></p>
<p><strong>#competition</strong></p>
<p><strong>#sweepstakes</strong></p>
<p><strong>#win</strong></p>
<p><strong>#prize</strong></p>
<p><strong>#giveawaycontest</strong></p>
<p><strong>#giveawayalert</strong></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Try our new Black Garlic Flavour Bomb!]]></title><description><![CDATA[Try the latest addition to the Original Black Garlic range.  Our black garlic is now in an innovative NEW handy sachets contain a single...]]></description><link>https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/post/try-our-new-flavour-bomb</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5fbe5e3510d821001754ac31</guid><category><![CDATA[food]]></category><category><![CDATA[health]]></category><pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 13:40:40 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_0c2f9aa718b840839fc182f4352b06de~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Katy </dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Try the latest addition to the <strong>Original Black Garlic</strong> range.
 
Our black garlic is now in an innovative <strong>NEW</strong> handy sachets contain a single 30ml  serve of our flavour bomb paste for maximum impact to your meal with <strong>no fuss!</strong>
 
Designed to suit your busy lifestyle, it gives you a quick and easy way to get our delicious sweet and savoury taste.  </p>
<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_472fd0586a9b48b68d940773b61c8c09~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_420,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_bd43f9c37e6249a583a70f68c75f9fcd~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_4e6baa5f175a4e9ca922921c29d500f8~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p>
 
It&apos;s perfect for use in soups and sauces or add a dollop (or two) to your chilli and bolognese to boost the richness of your flavours.  Or why not introduce some new flavour into butters, dips, marinade and stocks, be as creative as you want - that&apos;s what we love so much about black garlic.
 
For more recipes with black garlic <u><a href="https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/recipes-tips" target="_blank">click here</a></u>.
 
To make our new convenient sachet, the magic happens here in the UK, expertly aging white garlic to produce our rich and sticky black garlic paste, chefs and home cooks are really enthusiastic about the unique savoury edge.  
 
With all our products there is nothing added and no after smell guaranteed. 
 
<u><a href="https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/shop" target="_blank">Click here</a></u> to order and try for yourself.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why black garlic is an indispensable part of meat free living]]></title><description><![CDATA[Black garlic gives so many exciting ways to enhance your home meat free cuisine, as well as the added benefit of your physical resistance...]]></description><link>https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/post/why-black-garlic-as-an-indispensable-part-of-meat-free-living</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5fb518fb1e4bb00017757fc2</guid><category><![CDATA[food]]></category><category><![CDATA[health]]></category><category><![CDATA[vegan]]></category><pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 13:09:20 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_cd17ca9b52324387b683a376ad838a5d~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_443,h_457,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Katy </dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Black garlic gives so many exciting ways to enhance your home meat free cuisine, as well as the added benefit of your physical resistance to disease.  Think of it as your third seasoning; salt-pepper-black garlic and add it to dishes for the richness that it is sometimes hard to achieve without the fatty and saltiness of meat.  As well as carrying its own umami taste it deepens the flavour of your other ingredients <span style="color: #000000;">adding depth and piquancy to vegan, vegetarian meals.</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">Black garlic is produced by ageing regular garlic bulbs over weeks under carefully controlled conditions, with stringent adherence to specific humidity and temperature requirements in order to achieve its heady, delicious, treacle-like texture. This process results in the generation of twice the amount of antioxidants than you’ll find in the conventional version of garlic.  Less pungent than its raw white counterpart, black garlic has absolutely no after smell or after taste. </span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_cd17ca9b52324387b683a376ad838a5d~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_443,h_457,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_1267821fdece4eb4bc885164116963f8~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_478,h_474,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_2eac94cb65ba4af1bc2d97e8d44d445b~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_457,h_463,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Black garlic cloves can also been eaten as a snack, eating just two to three cloves per day make the difference between a compromised immune system and a robust one. In this day and age, why take the chance of not doing all you can to build your body’s resistant to infection and disease.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">It is as soft as a jelly baby and almost as sweet! This means children are happy to consider it as a between-meals treat without realising they are actually eating a tasty snack that is actively assisting the strength of their immune system and exponentially building their resistance to disease and infection.</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[15 top tips for easy ways to bring black garlic into your kitchen ]]></title><description><![CDATA[Although it has a totally unique taste, there’s a huge range of ways black garlic can be used for. Here's our 15 top tips for easy ways...]]></description><link>https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/post/15-top-tips-for-easy-ways-to-bring-black-garlic-into-your-kitchen</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5fb394cf5cc48c0017081361</guid><category><![CDATA[food]]></category><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 09:28:18 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_a372867d0e594505bc8bcc365bf8951d~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_603,h_455,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Katy </dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Although it has a totally unique taste, there’s a huge range of ways black garlic can be used for.</p>
<p>Here&apos;s our 15 top tips for easy ways to bring black garlic into your kitchen:</p>
<ol>
  <li><p>Mash some cloves with some soy sauce and chilli for an alternative stir-fry sauce.</p></li>
  <li><p>Combine cloves with cream cheese and herbs for a tasty dip.</p></li>
  <li><p>Puree some cloves with oil to create a paste then smear onto chicken or fish before roasting.</p></li>
  <li><p>Add some cloves to <u>Bolognese</u> or <u>Chilli</u> to enhance flavours.</p></li>
  <li><p>Mash a few cloves into a meatball mixture.</p></li>
  <li><p>Slice thinly and use to top salads.</p></li>
  <li><p>Add to cheese on toast for a special twist.</p></li>
  <li><p>Dip into melted dark chocolate for a sweet taste sensation <em>(try it with some Green &amp; Blacks 70% Cocoa Dark Chocolate, available in the Gousto Marketplace).</em></p></li>
  <li><p>Blend some cloves with mayo and serve with burgers or chips.</p></li>
  <li><p>Add a few cloves into <u>macaroni cheese</u> or <u>cauliflower cheese</u>.</p></li>
  <li><p>Pair with cheese such as on a cheeseboard replacing chutney with black garlic.</p></li>
  <li><p>Add a sprinkle of water to cloves and blend with a good quality olive oil for an alternative salad dressing.</p></li>
  <li><p>Mix crushed cloves into a homemade tomato sauce and use with pasta or spread as a sauce base on a pizza.</p></li>
  <li><p>Pop the delicious cloves straight in your mouth!</p></li>
  <li><p>Use it in your own culinary experiments…let us know how you like to use black garlic in the comments section below!
</p></li>
</ol>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/7e8186_0843980fd313481e9167a10b80322114~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Discover more exciting ways to use black garlic <u><a href="https://www.blackgarlic.co.uk/recipes-tips" target="_blank">here.</a></u></p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>